Every dog happens for a reason.
A Dog's Purpose is a adventure, comedy, fantasy
film directed by Lasse Hallström.
A dog goes on quest to discover his purpose in life over the
course of several lifetimes with multiple owners.
Dogs: Bailey / Buddy / Tino / Ellie (voice), played by Josh Gad.
Teen Ethan, played by KJ Apa.
Teen Hannah, played by Britt Robertson.
Adult Ethan, played by Dennis Quaid.
Adult Hannah, played by Peggy Lipton.
Elizabeth - Ethan's Mom, played by Juliet Rylance.
A Dog's Purpose is a 2017 American adventure comedy-drama film
directed by Lasse Hallström and written by W.
Bruce Cameron, Cathryn Michon, Audrey Wells, Maya Forbes, and Wally
Wolodarsky, based on the 2010 novel of the same name by W.
Bruce Cameron.
The film stars Britt Robertson, KJ Apa in his film debut, Juliet Rylance, John
Ortiz and Dennis Quaid with Josh Gad in multiple voice roles.
It explores themes of loyalty, grief, and dysfunctional
families over a series of reincarnations.
The film is a co-production between Amblin Entertainment, Reliance
Entertainment, Walden Media, and Pariah Entertainment Group.
It was released by Universal Pictures on January 27, 2017, and grossed $205
million worldwide, and received mixed reviews from critics.
It was Peggy Lipton's final film role before her death in 2019.
A sequel, titled A Dog's Journey, was released on May 17, 2019.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, human
animal relationship, reincarnation, dog, pets.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.